Brian Wigginton

Software Engineer

Austin, Texas brianwigginton@gmail.com https://bwiggs.com

Smart and empathetic Software Engineer with vast experience in different domains and technologies. From fast paced startups and advertising shops, to large scale insuretech. From large multiteam projects to individual projects. I love working on teams with excited and passionate people out to solve interesting problems.

LinkedIn: wiggintonbrian

Github: bwiggs

Keybase: bwigginton

Experience

Development Manager, Data Products

Applied Systems Austin, Texas Jul 2019 - Sep 2021

Managed 10 direct reports, responsible for weekly 1-1s, annual reviews, hiring new talent. Collaborated closely with Product Owners, QA, Architecture and DevOps teams for delivery of new features.

- Enterprise Data Lake Lead a new team towards building a customer-facing Data Lake leveraging GCP, GKE and BigQuery
- Data Warehouse Migration Managed the team working on converting a legacy SQLServer data warehouse system to Google BigQuery. **Speedup from minutes to seconds.**
- Applied Analytics Managed the product engineering team working on new features and integrations.

Senior Software Engineer

Applied Systems Sep 2015 - Jul 2019

• Applied Analytics - Lead a team in rebuilding Applied Analytics using a new microservices architecture using Kubernetes, GKE, GoLang, GRPC, REST, API Gateway Pattern, JWTs, Datadog, Docker and ArgoCD deploying to GCP.

- Project Mobius Created a web frontend for Applied's flagship software, Epic. There were no APIs, so we had to reverse engineer a proprietary .NET API Protocol. Using GoLang and Angular 4.
- AL3 RLE Processor Developed custom AL3 RLE file parser using GoLang to scrape millions of commercial insurance policy records.
- Kraken Built a data ingestion platform using GoLang, Angular and Postgres. Centralized data from thousands of custom databases into a centralized data store for use by our product team.

JavaScript Instructor

General Assembly Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Instructor for a 10 week night-class of 8 junior JavaScript developers. Helped several students gain full-time engineering jobs once the class was finished!

Senior Software Engineer

Evosure Austin, Texas Nov 2014 - Sep 2015

8th hire at Evosure, a startup in the Insuretech space. We were acquired by Applied Systems in 2015.

- Full Stack Engineer GoLang, Postgres, Ruby, Angular, CircleCl and AWS.
- Industry Search API Developed an API to help users find relevant industries from SIC, NAICS, SIC-UK classification systems. Leveraged GoLang, Postgres, AWS. Feature was well received and rolled out to other teams at Applied as well as the core Epic Software.

Senior Software Engineer

Sportslabs Boulder, CO Dec 2012 - Aug 2014

- Campus Insiders Rewrote from PHP Silex to Ruby on Rails. Cloudfront CDN, SOLR for full-text search, HAProxy L7 routing to let us do phased deployments.
- Team Lead for Custom CMS tool and visual redesign rollout of Campus Insiders
- Culture Squad Put together a team to work on culture impact at SL. We created

another.

Technical Lead

Crispin Porter + Bogusky Boulder, CO Mar 2012 - Nov 2012

Lead development teams to deliver applications using a wide range of technologies.

- Lead rollout of Agile to a team of 20+ developers to deliver software. Wrote stories, estimation, story breakdowns. Mentored junior engineers.
- American Express, Applebees, MDC Partners

Senior Interactive Developer

Crispin Porter + Bogusky Boulder, CO Jul 2010 - Jul 2011

Vail Resort's EpicMix: JavaScript, HTML/CSS, C#

Freelance Web Developer

Self Employeed Fort Worth, TX Apr 2009 - Jul 2010

- MDC Partners Wrote backend for new web experience for MDC partners. Ingest data from several sources to show MDC executives on a map and recent activit. CakePHP 1.2, REST API for Flash frontend
- NGMOCO: Rolando Character Creator, Promotion Management tool
- Other projects: Magento Ecommerce site, Joomla CMS implementations, Drupal implementations.

Interactive Project Manager + Web Application Developer

Algo+Rhythm/Rassai Fort Worth, TX May 2008 - Jul 2009

Worked with inhouse and remote development/design team to deliver client projects.

Skills

PROGRAMMING

Go, JavaScript, Ruby, Python, HTML, CSS, PHP, Perl

FRAMEWORKS

Vue.js, Angular, Echo (GoLang), TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, GTK3

CLOUDS

Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS)

AGILE

Scrum, Kanban

CI/CD

Gitlab, Github, Git, CircleCI, ArgoCD

OBSERVABILITY

Datadog, New Relic, Google Stackdriver, Grafana

API DEVELOPMENT

GRPC, REST, OAS, API Gateway, Swagger

CONTAINERS

Kubernetes, GKE, Docker, Docker Compose

DATA LAKE/DATA MESH

BigQuery, S3, GCS

DATABASES

Postgres, SqlServer, MySQL

LEADERSHIP

Manager, Tech Lead, Teacher, Mentor

AUTOMATED TESTING

Selenium, Artillery, ab

APPLICATIONS

JIRA, Confluence, Slack, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, 1Password, Office365

STRENGTHS FINDER

Relator, Restorative, Responsibility, Adaptability, Focus

Education

Texas Christian University

BS, Computer Information Technology

Aug 2004 - May 2008

References

"At SportsLabs, Brian provided a crucial senior leadership role. He was able to bring out the best in his teammates by example and instruction, by balancing pragmatic and agile programming, and by sponsoring tech talks in and outside of the company."

Scott Symmank

"If I was fighting in combat, this is the guy I'd want by my side."

– Justin Kent

"I've worked with Brian for over a year. He is very dependable, skilled and has a unquenchable thirst for learning new technologies. He will always get the job done. He has strong skills in both web project management and in web production."

Aaron Benson

"Brian is such an enthusiastic person to work with. He enjoys sharing his knowledge with others and does so with such passion and drive. I really hope to work with Brian again in the future. His fuel can feed so many people on a team and his constant smile is very positive to those around him. Brian, I wish you the best and really hope you'll keep in touch and I'm honored to have you as part of my LinkedIn Network."

— Billy Clark

"Detailed and Creative. Friendly and easy to work with. Very knowledgeable with a good eye on current trends. Can't wait to work with him again."

- Ryan Gibbons

Interests

CYCLING

Either on the road or on the Peloton.

COFFEE

Espresso, Pour Over, Aeropress it's all good!

HOMELAB

SCIENCE FICTION

Love some great scifi! Favorite Book: Hyperion

LACROSSE

My High School and Collegiate sport! Still love watching games.

TV SHOWS

Seinfeld, Arrested Development